<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Amir-Hossein</title>
    <link>https://amirshahid.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://amirshahid.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://amirshahid.github.io/images/icon_huf961c08f3fa341d50065c39a43445549_299843_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://amirshahid.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Slide Scanner</title>
      <link>https://amirshahid.github.io/project/scanner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amirshahid.github.io/project/scanner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First of all, please watch the slides on the top&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\ \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\ \ \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pushing the limits of AI by inventing a scanner for detecting cancerous cells from medical images using Neural Networks.
this patented capture technology is an automated scanner for medical images which enables pathological experts to work remotely with laboratory microscopes from home or anywhere with internet access.
The process of scanning consists of &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iterating the slides and captures high-quality images using super-resolution cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stitching the captured images regarding to camera movement error in microscopic scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;give images to our deep neural networks for diagnosis purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We benefit from our own built dataset in training purposes.
I am in the Computer Vision team and have contributed to Stitching, PapSmear Cancer Classification, Cell Segmentation, Cell Counting, Streaming in Python and C++.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transfer Learning in RL</title>
      <link>https://amirshahid.github.io/project/bs-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amirshahid.github.io/project/bs-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\  \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\   \   \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My BSc thesis under the supervision of Prof. Rabiee was
about Applications of Transfer Learning in Reinforcement Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my research on self-driving cars (SDV),
I was impressed by the reinforcement learning algorithms&#39; effect on SDV, but these algorithms heavily rely on expensive sensors like LiDAR, multi-camera, and 3d-camera, etc. which is conducive to the high price of such vehicles these days. Therefore, I was inclined to avoid the collisions only with the help of a single camera (monocular image) and high-level feature extractor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, in this thesis, I have tried to train in a simulator to minimize real-world collision due to such systems&#39; criticality and deployed transfer learning methods to handle distribution shifts between simulation and real-world images.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
